Guide to the Records of the Institute of African American Affairs RG.9.8
New York University Archives
Records of the Institute of African American Affairs
1965-2018
New York University Archives
New York University. Institute of African-American Affairs.
NAME OF CREATOR
RG.9.8
114
96.17 Linear Feet in 90 record cartons, 12 manuscript boxes, and 1 flat box.
54 film reels
161 3.5" floppy disks
47 electronic discs (cd-rom)
2 dvd-r disks
175 videocassettes (digital betacam)
319 videocassettes (vhs)
282 audiocassettes
54 videocassettes (minidv)
4 videocassettes (dvcam)
22 sound discs (cd)
1 videocassettes (u-matic)
The Institute of African American Affairs (IAAA) at New York University was founded in 1969 to research, document, and celebrate the cultural and intellectual production of Africa and its diaspora. Today, IAAA remains committed to the study of Blacks in modernity through concentrations in Pan-Africanism and Black Urban Studies. The Records of the Institute of African American Affairs date from 1965 to the early 1990s. Included is correspondence from the late 1980s and early 1990s from Earl S. Davis, one of IAAA's directors, as well as conference and event materials, and information about Association of Education in Journalism internships. The collection also contains 266 recordings dating from 1971 to 1986 of The Soul of Reason, a radio talk show that aired on commercial radio station WNBC and NYU's station WNYU. The Records of the Institute of African American Affairs 2018 accretion includes event material relating to conferences and programs dating from 1993 to 2003.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged chronologically. Series IV: Audiovisual Recordings is divided into two sub-series: IV.A: Soul of Reason Audio Recordings and IV.B: Other Audio Recordings.
The June 2018 accretion to the Records of the Institute of Afro-American Affairs are added to Series I. Events and Series IV., Subseries B: Other Audio Recordings. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
The December 2018 accretion to the Records of the Institute of Afro-American Affairs are added to Series I. and Series IV, Subseries C: Unprocessed Materials. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
The files are grouped into four series:
Missing Title
Events Files
Association for Education in Journalism
Earl S. Davis Correspondence
Audiovisual Recordings
Scope and Content Note
The Records of the Institute of African American Affairs date from 1965 to 2018. Included is correspondence from the late 1980s and early 1990s from Earl S. Davis, one of IAAA's directors, as well as conference and event materials, and information about Association of Education in Journalism internships. The collection also contains 266 recordings of The Soul of Reason, a radio talk show that aired on commercial radio station WNBC and later on NYU's station WNYU. The collection contains a portion of The Soul of Reason shows that initially aired between 1971 and 1978, with interviewees ranging from politicians to professional athletes to medical professionals to contemporary artists.
The Records of the Institute of African American Affairs 2018 accretions include event material relating to conferences and programs created by the Institute for Afro-American Affairs from 1993 to 2003. Recordings of these event discussions are found on 876 audiovisual recordings and 210 born digital materials.
The publication Black Renaissance Noire and event material relating to conferences and programs presented by the Institute from 1993 to 2018 are part of a separate 2018 accretion.
Historical Note
The Institute of Afro-American Affairs at New York University was founded in 1969 to research, document, and celebrate the cultural and intellectual production of Africa and its diaspora in the Atlantic world and beyond. The Institute is affiliated and shares leadership, staff, and facilities with NYU's Africana Studies Program. Both organizations are committed to the study of Blacks in modernity through concentrations in Pan-Africanism and Black Urban Studies. Now called the Institute of African American Affairs, the Institute each year brings to NYU Artists and Scholars-in-Residence, who during their residencies participate in seminars, offer public presentations of their work, and meet with students. Past Artists-in-Residence have included author Walter Mosley; poet and essayist Amiri Baraka; actor, playwright, and performance artist Anna Deavere Smith; poet Jayne Cortez; actor and producer Danny Glover; and Malian musician Salif Keita. Scholars-in-Residence have included Nigerian author and Nobel Laureate Wole Soyinka; and David Levering Lewis, MacArthur Fellow and Martin Luther King, Jr. Professor of History at Rutgers.
Sources:
Afro-American Affairs, Institute of, Archives H, NYU Archives.
Access Restrictions
Institutional records of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation (the date on which each document was written). Board of Trustees records are similarly closed for 35 years from the date of creation. The opening date for files spanning several years will be 20 years from the most recent date. Access will be given to material already 20 years old contained within a collection that is not yet open when such material can be isolated from the rest of the collection.
Materials related to personnel, faculty grievances, job searches and all files with information that falls under the University's Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) policy are permanently restricted.
Please contact the University Archivists with specific questions regarding restrictions.
Provenance
This collection was transferred to the University Archives in 1994.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
The Soul of Reason audio recordings in Series IV.A. have been digitized and are available to stream via the finding aid.
Audiovisual materials that have not been preserved are not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact university-archives@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
June 2018 Accretion transferred by the Institute of African American Affairs, 2018. The accession number associated with this transfer is 2018.018.
The December 2018 Accretion was transferred by Jaira Placide, Associate Director, Institute of African American Affairs and Center for Black Visual Culture on July 2018.The accession number associated with this deposit is 2018.044.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies. To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact university-archives@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Appraisal
Extra copies of Black Renaissance Noire were discarded according to New York University's Special Collections Deaccessioning Policy.
Correspondence.; Administrative records.; American literature -- African American authors.; African American theater; African American athletes; Clippings (information artifacts); African Americans |x Mental health; American literature |x Puerto Rican authors; Audiovisual materials.; African Americans -- Economic conditions.; Puerto Rican families -- New York (State) -- New York.; African Americans -- Politics and government.; African American art.; Reports.; African American college students.; Audiocassettes.; Pamphlets.; Lectures.; VHS; Press releases.; New York University. Institute of African-American Affairs.; Davis, Earl S.; Brown, Roscoe Conkling, Jr., 1922-
- Series I: Events Files, 61505
  - Black Scholars Lecture Series: "The Black Church in the 80's" Rev. Herbert Daughtry, 1978-1982; 61726 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    Barcode #: 31142042260185
  - Emerging African Nations, 1978-1982; 61725 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04226018 5
  - MLK Memorial Concert, 1978-1982; 61724 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Benin Catalog Orders/Sales, Exhibition Date 1981 - Present (Receipts of Payment), 61723 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Benin Exhibition "Images of Power" Correspondence, 1981; 61722 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Benin Exhibition Listings, 1981; 61721 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Benin Exhibition Publicity, 1981; 61720 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Benin Exhibition "Images of Power" Publicity, 1981; 61719 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Black Scholars Lecture Series: "The Labor Union Movement - It's Importance in Developing Countries"/ Lillian Roberts, Speaker., 1978-1982; 61718 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Honorable Robert Davis, Comm. Lecture. Series, 1978-1982; 61717 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Black Scholar Lecture Series: "Housing Trends in the Black Community: What Will the 80's Bring", 1978-1982; 61716 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Black History Reception, 1982; 61715 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Black History Month Reception, Feb 4, 1982; 61714 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Community Lecture Series: Rev. Daughtry, Feb 23, 1982; 61713 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Community Lecture Series: Dr. Albert Oliver, Mar 16, 1982; 61712 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Cinema Series "Common Denominators" -, Mar 30, 1982; 61711 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Black Male Conference Part I: Correspondence - Speakers., Mar 30, 1982; 61710 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Black Male Conference Part I: Correspondence - Forms, 1982; 61709 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Black Male Conference Part I: Correspondence - Personalized, 1982; 61708 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Black Male Conference Part I: Forms, 1982; 61707 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Black Male Conference Part I: Program Operation, Logistics, 1982; 61706 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Black Male Conference Part I: Public Correspondence - Info. Requests, Comments, Etc., 1982; 61705 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Black Male Conference Part I: Publicity, 1982; 61704 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Registrants Forms/Responses, & Questionnaire Responses, Part I: Black Male Conference, 1982; 61703 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Black Male Conference Pt. I: Speakers' Papers/Correspondence., 1982; 61702 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Black Male Conference Pt. I: Topic Information, 1982; 61701 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Black Male Conference Pt. I: Programming, Logistics, Logistics-Operation, 1982; 61700 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Dr. Wyatt T. Walker, Apr 12, 1982; 61699 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Martin Luther King Salute: Canaan Baptist Church, Apr 12, 1982; 61698 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Black Theatre Forum - Correspondence to Speakers/Participants, 1982; 61697 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Black Theatre Forum Conference Expenditures, Revenues, & Pre-registration, 1982; 61696 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Black Theatre Forum Conference Forms, 1982; 61695 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Black Theatre Forum Conference Forms, 1982; 61694 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Black Theatre Forum Conference Funding: Proposals & Correspondence, 1982; 61693 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Black Male Conference Pt. II: Correspondence/Form Letters to Lecturers/Speakers., 1982; 61692 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Black Male Conference Pt. II: Advance Registration Forms/Responses, 1982; 61691 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04226019 3
  - Black Male Conference Correspondence-Personalized Pt. II:, 1982; 61690 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Black Male Conference Pt. II: Forms, 1982; 61689 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Black Male Conference Pt. 2 Lecturer/Speaker. Responses, 1982; 61688 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Black Male Conference Pt. II: Lecturer/Speaker. Responses, Correspondence, Papers, 1982; 61687 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Black Male Conference Pt. II: Papers of Speakers, 1982; 61686 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Black Male Conference Pt. II: Pgm. Operation/Logistics & Publicity, 1982; 61685 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Black Male Conference Pt. II: Public Correspondence, 1982; 61684 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Black Male Conference Pt. II: Questionnaires to Public Responses, 1982; 61683 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Black Male Conference Pt. II: Registrants Forms/Responses, 1982; 61682 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Black Male Conference Pt. II: Speakers Info., 1982; 61681 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Black Male Conference Pt. II: Workshop(s) Info., 1982; 61680 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Making America Work Exhibition: Exhibition Budget & Expenses, Feb 3, 1983-Feb 18, 1983; 61679 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Making America Work Exhibition: External Correspondence concerning Exhibition, Feb 3, 1983-Feb 18, 1983; 61678 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Making America Work Exhibition: Patents and Pictures of Exhibition, Feb 3, 1983-Feb 18, 1983; 61677 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Making America Work Exhibition: Chronological Files, Feb 3, 1983-Feb 18, 1983; 61676 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Making America Work Exhibition: External Correspondence regarding exhibition, Feb 3, 1983-Feb 18, 1983; 61675 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Making America Work Exhibition: University Correspondence regarding exhibition, Feb 3, 1983-Feb 18, 1983; 61674 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Making America Work Exhibition, Feb 3, 1983-Feb 18, 1983; 61673 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Blacks in the West; W.L. Katz, Prof., Feb 4, 1983; 61672 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Black History Month Reception: A Salute to Paul Robeson, Feb 7, 1983; 61671 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Black History Month Reception: Paul Robeson Tribute, 1982-1983; 61670 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04226020 1
  - Dennis Rahim Watson, Ben Snow - Bobst, Feb 16, 1983; 61669 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Community Lecture Series: E. Graves, Feb 23, 1982; 61668 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Black Theatre Forum-Conference, Program Operation: Logistics, Budget, Programming, 1982; 61667 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Black Theatre Forum-Conference: Publicity, 1982; 61666 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Black Theatre Forum: 'A Total Perspective" Questionnaires, 1982; 61665 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Black Theatre Forum-Conference: Related Literature/Topics, 1982; 61664 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Black Theatre Forum-Conference, Speakers: Papers, Corres., Bio-Info., 1982; 61663 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Black Theatre Forum-Conference: Speaker/Possible Participants Correspondence, 1982; 61662 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Black Theatre Forum-Conference: Speakers-Speeches, Lectures, 1982; 61661 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Association of Black Women in Higher Education, Inc. 4th Annual Conference, May 7, 1982; 61660 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Caribbean Conference Correspondence (Speaker(s) Solicitation), Letters., 1982; 61659 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Caribbean Conf. Forms, 1982; 61658 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Caribbean Conf. Letrs. of Responses & Returned Forms (Call for Papers), 1982; 61657 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Caribbean Conf. "Caribbean Culture & Politics: Today's Realities-Tomorrow's Directions," -- Program Operation (i.e. schedules, expenses), 1982; 61656 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Caribbean Conference: "Caribbean Culture & Politics: Today's Realities-Tomorrow's Directions," Publicity, 1982; 61655 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Caribbean Conference: Related info, 1982; 61654 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Series V. Community Lecture Series: Dr. Ben -Jochannon, May 17, 1982; 61653 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Community Lecture Series: Alice Childress, Oct 19, 1982; 61652 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Black Theater Forum: Correspondence-Earl Davis, 1982; 61651 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Black Theater Forum Conference: IAAA Correspondence (1), 1982; 61650 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Theater Mailing List, 1982-1983; 61649 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Black Theater Forum Conference: IAAA Correspondence (2), 1982; 61648 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Association of Black Faculty & Students, 1983-1984; 61647 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Black History Reception, 1984; 61646 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Community Lecture Series II: Robinson, Randall, 1983-1984; 61645 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Catti James, undated; 61644 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Cinema Presentations, 1983-1984; 61643 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Community Lecture Series III: Cross, Dr. Delores (1), 1983-1984; 61642 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Twelfth Annual Dr. Martin L. King Jr., Memorial Concert, 1983-1984; 61641 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Lecture "The IAAA at NYU" Spkr.: Earl Davis, 1983-1984; 61640 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Program Schedules & Operations, 1983-1984; 61639 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Minority Student/Faculty Reception 10/10/84, Oct 10, 1984; 61638 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Tom Sanders: Community Lecture Series I - Black Athletes Responsibility to the Black Community, 1983-1984; 61637 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Cal Ramsay: Community Lecture Series I "The Black Athletes' Responsibility to the Black Community", 1983-1984; 61636 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Paula Giddings 11/19/84, undated; 61635 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Paula Giddings: Community Lecture Series II: "When and Where I Enter", 1983-1984; 61634 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Black History Reception '85 "Diggers, Panama Canal: Creation of a Nation", 1983-1984; 61633 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Making America Work: Black Contributions To American Business And Industry; Exhibition Paper by L. Bray; Pictures; Flyers, 1983-1984; 61632 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - News Articles, 1983-1984; 61631 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Community Lecture Series III: Cross, Dr. Delores (2), 1983-1984; 61630 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04226021 9
  - Community Lecture Series V: Dr. Carlos Moore, 1983-1984; 61629 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Dr. Carlos Moore, 1983-1984; 61628 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Advertising & Press Releases, 1983-1984; 61627 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Budget & Program Planning, 1983-1984; 61626 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Conference Flyers & Programs, 1983-1984; 61625 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1984; 61624 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Black History Month Reception: "Diggers, Panama Canal: Creation of a Nation" Ben Snow, Bobst Library, Feb 4, 1985; 61623 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Black History Calendar Reception - Bobst Library, Feb 4, 1985; 61622 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Judge Bruce Wright Lecture Series, Feb 13, 1985; 61621 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Catti James -Lecture Workshop "Celebration: Experiences in Black Art", Feb 13, 1985; 61620 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Essence - Susan Taylor "An Agenda For the Future Economic Empowerment and Love" (1), Mar 18, 1985; 61619 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Susan Taylor "An Agenda For the Future Economic Empowerment and Love" (2), Mar 18, 1985; 61618 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - National Association Black Counselors; The National Organizational Conference, Apr 2, 1985; 61617 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - The National Association of Black Counselors --- The Nat'l Organizational Conference, Mar 31, 1985-Apr 5, 1985; 61616 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Afro-Brazilian Territory, Apr 24, 1985; 61615 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Association of Black Women in Higher Education, Inc. 7th Annual Conference, 1985-1986; 61614 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Paule Marshall - Community Lecture Series, Oct 16, 1986; 61613 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Dr. Michael Crowder, Oct 24, 1985; 61612 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Black Film Festival, Oct 28, 1985-Oct 30, 1985; 61611 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - National Women's Conference in Nairobi, Kenya, Oct 12, 1985; 61610 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04226022 7
  - Community Symposium: Free Enterprise versus Military Rule in Third World Countries, Oct 25, 1985; 61609 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - A Special Tribute in celebration of Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., Ben Snow Lounge, Jan 15, 1986; 61608 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - [Living the Dream], 1985-1986; 61607 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Lecture: "Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.: An African Perception." by Dr. John Kerefa-Smart, Feb 3, 1986; 61606 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - The Invisible America: "The Next Generation", Feb 7, 1986; 61605 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Photography Exhibition, Feb 7, 1986; 61604 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence/Photographers, Feb 7, 1986; 61603 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Photo Exhibit-Correspondence (Program Operation, Forms, Etc), Feb 7, 1986; 61602 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Photo Exhibit-Correspondence (Unselected Photographers), Feb 7, 1986; 61601 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Photo Exhibition Programming: Planning, Operations, Budget & Logistical Set Up, Feb 7, 1986; 61600 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Program Funding, Solicitation of Sponsorship, Photo Exhibition, 1985-1986; 61599 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Photographer Listings, Feb 7, 1986; 61598 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Photo Exhibit - Photographers' Prints/Entered in Exhibition (1), Feb 7, 1986; 61597 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Photo Exhibition Publicity, Press Releases, Commentaries, Etc., Feb 7, 1986; 61596 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Photography Exhibition, 1986; 61595 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Photography Exhibition, 1985-1986; 61594 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Photography Exhibit - Photographers' Prints/Entered in Exhibition (2), 2/7/86, Feb 7, 1986; 61593 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Photography Exhibition (2), 1986; 61592 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - David Dinkins, Feb 10, 1986; 61591 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Health Issues in the Black Community: Prognosis for Change, undated; 61590 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Black History Month Film Festival, Feb 24, 1986-Feb 27, 1986; 61589 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04226023 5
  - African Film Festival, Feb 24, 1986-Feb 27, 1986; 61588 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - "Malcolm X -The Master Teacher", Mar 3, 1986; 61587 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Community Lecture Series - "Women of the Royal Court of Benin"., Mar 20, 1986; 61586 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Dr. Angelina Pollack-Eltz, Afro-American Folk Medicine, Apr 2, 1986; 61585 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Poetry Reading: Fred Ramey, Betty Lawrence Bailey, May 12, 1986; 61584 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - South Africa: A Nation in Crisis, Sep 22, 1986; 61583 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - IAAA's First Annual Fundraising Cabaret Dinner Dance at CJ's Seafood Restaurant, Oct 12, 1986; 61582 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Minority Students Fall Orientation, Fall 1986; 61581 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - The Simpson/Rodino Bill: Impact on Minority Communities, undated; 61580 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - "The Civil Rights Struggle Continued - 25 Years Later": Reception-Dr. Martin L. King, Jr., Jan 15, 1987; 61579 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Community Lecture Series: "Gov't & Politics in NYC-Implications for the Minority Community", Jan 27, 1987; 61578 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Black History Month, Feb 3, 1987; 61577 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Black Filmmakers Mini-Film Festival 87: "Your Children Come Back to You," Alile Larkin; "Grey Area," Monona IAAA Reception, Theme: "Continent to Continent: A Ritual Experience", Feb 12, 1987; 61576 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - IAAA Reception, Theme: Continent to Continent: A Ritual Experience", Feb 12, 1987; 61575 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - "The Role of the Police Officer in the Minority Community" event cancelled, 2/12/87, undated; 61574 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - "A Tribute to Civil Rights Leaders, Lest We Forget", Feb 25, 1987; 61573 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Annual ABFA Student/Faculty Basketball Game, Feb 27, 1987; 61572 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - GPA Marnold Fellow Program; Speakers: Earl S. Davis, Hon. Charles B. Rangel & Dean Alan Altshuler, GPA, Apr 6, 1987; 61571 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - "Perceptions of Visual Structure as an Attitude of Non-Objective Art: Tools for the Layman to Evaluate Art," Dr. Adrienne W. Hoard, Guest Speaker, Apr 30, 1987; 61570 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Blind Beggar Press: 6th Annual Book Celebration, May 7, 1987; 61569 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Black Faculty/Administrator/Student Orientation, 1987; 61568 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - "Mandela" - Movie/video, Nov 9, 1987; 61567 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Ted Joans - Poet, "One of the last Black Bohemian-Beat Generation Poets", 1987; 61566 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Blacks and the Constitution (symposium), 1987; 61565 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Kwanza, Dec 7, 1987; 61564 (Box 6, Folder 27)